Arit Shom Dey

Content Marketer | Technical Writer | Team Lead

<u>LinkedIn</u> | Email: arit.dey7@gmail.com | Mobile: +919051660830 | Portfolio

<u>Professional Summary</u>

Highly motivated with extensive knowledge in communication, team management, SEO, market research, data analysis, database management and technical writing - Constantly focused on optimizing productivity and delivery, enhancing quality, surpassing the SLA metrics, and improving the TAT and workflow to ensure effective cost management, process integrity and profitability.

Skills

- Copywriting, Editing & Training
- Digital Marketing & Content Strategy
- Market Research, PPC & SEO
- Technical Writing, Structuring & Markup
- Data Analysis & Dashboarding
- SQL & Database Management
- Leadership & Team Management
- Graphic Design & Instructional Design

Tools

- MS Office & Google Suite
- Google Analytics, Semrush & Ahrefs
- WordPress & Generative AI
- GitHub, Markdown, GitHub Wiki

- Advanced MS Excel & VBA
- PostgreSQL, MySQL & Oracle
- Canva, Photoshop & Lightroom
- DITA, Oxygen XML Author & HTML

Work Experience

Content Marketing Specialist | Comfort Click Softech Pvt. Ltd. | Hyderabad

May, 2023 - Present

- Creating engaging web content for in-house Brands' products, SEO, PPC, email marketing, ad copies, and social media.
- Curating and maintaining Product Documentation and Process SOPs for the company's internal records and training; analyzing user data and internal data for effective strategizing.
- Collaborating with different stakeholders across various channels and departments to share ideas and insights.

Editor | Das Writing Services Pvt. Ltd. | Kolkata

Sep, 2021 – Aug, 2022

- Curating and editing various search-engine-optimized content for Academic, Technical, and Finance projects.
- Managing a team of 8-10 writers in terms of quality, efficiency, and productivity; maintaining their performance data and handling team reviews as per KRA and SLA metrics.
- Efficiently carried out the duties of being a POC for several clients in terms of discussing ideas and gathering feedback.

Freelance Technical Writer | All Things How | Kolkata

Feb, 2021 – Aug, 2021

- Writing Search Engine Optimized technical blogs, how-to articles, product descriptions, UI guides, tech reviews, and tutorials.
- Working directly on WordPress to provide optimal user experience via enhanced readability, interactive infographics and embedded add-on content.
- Conducting in-depth keyword research and analysis in Semrush, Ahrefs, and Google Keyword Planner for enhanced visibility.

Senior Associate | Netscribes India Pvt. Ltd. | Kolkata

Nov, 2017 - Nov, 2020

- Conducting marketplace cataloging, product mapping, curating catchy product descriptions, and Quality Audit of the content generated by my team.
- Leading a team of 12-15 Associates and driving SLA-based project metrics through interactive training modules to improve team
 efficiency
- Carrying out the duties of being a liaison to the clients efficiently; delivering and implementing their feedback to my team.

Education

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science & Engineering, WBUT (2017)

Certifications

- Technical Writing: How to Write Software Documentation Udemy
- The Complete SQL Bootcamp: Go from Zero to Hero Udemy
- Microsoft Excel Excel from Beginner to Advanced Udemy
- Graphic Design with Photoshop Great Learning Academy
- Digital Marketing Great Learning Academy
- Content Marketing Great Learning Academy
- Google Analytics 4 Great Learning Academy